Guide to the Park City Mountain Resort audio-visual collection 1961-2002
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
- Park City Pro Cup television news coverage, 1988 November 18-28; VHS videocassette (Cassette 53)
  These news reports discuss the planned events for the weekend of the Pro Cup Skiing race in Park City Utah. They showcase the Mahre brothers who are returning to competitive ski racing after a four-year hiatus after winning Olympic medals in Sarajevo. They show action shots of past Pro Cup winners and discuss dates, times, locations, and ticket information.
- Park City Pro Cup awards footage, 1988 November 23; Betacam videocassette (Cassette 54)
  Footage of the awards ceremony for the 1988 Pro Cup held in Park City, Utah.
- Park City Pro Cup, 1988 November 30; VHS videocassette (Cassette 55)
  This is footage from the Pro Cup skiing event held at Park City, Utah. Featured are the men's and women's qualifying races, the men's slalom and giant slalom as well as the women's slalom and giant slalom.
- Utah Connections - Americas Opening in Park City, 1988 December 02; VHS videocassette (Cassette 56)
  Images of professional skiers, judges, ski lifts, hot air balloons, spectators, etc accompanied by music. This video appears to be a background piece intended to be used as visual filler during a newscast or similar type of television program. Running time: Approximately 4 minutes.
- Television news coverage, 1988 December 05-21; VHS videocassette > (Cassette 57)
  12/5/88 KSTU Utah Connections Ski Trips with Scott Cross Pt. 1
  12/6/88 KSTU Utah Connections Ski Trips with Scott Cross Pt. 2
  12/7/88 KSTU Utah Connections Ski Trips with Scott Cross Pt. 3
  12/8/88 KSTU Utah Connections Ski Trips with Scott Cross Pt. 4
  12/9/88 KSTU Utah Connections Ski Trips with Scott Cross Pt. 5
  12/8/88 KTVX 5:30 pm Japanese Skiing in Utah (Menlove).
  12/8/88 KTVX 10:00 pm (Voice Over)
  12/11/88 KTVX 10:00 pm Handicapped Ski Program.
  12/12/88 KUTV 6:00 pm Park City, etc. prepare for Japanese skiers.
  12/20/88 KTVX 5:30 pm Park City, etc. are booked.
  12/21/88 KUTV 6:00 pm Ski Resorts want to keep sales tax.
  Park City's 25th Anniversary (one clip).
  12/21/88 KTVX 5:30 pm Ski resorts want to keep sales tax.
- PM Magazine in Orlando, 1988; VHS videocassette (Cassette 58)
  This tape consists of a television news story concerning Park City ski resort. The story is about the Utah ski industry as a whole and hosts Beth Wood and Bob Gossler discuss Park City Ski Area in particular.
  Other news stories included in the same episode feature Donald Trump and the disc jockey who inspired the film, Good Morning, Vietnam (Barry Levinson 1987).
- America's Opening: Park City Pro Cup, 1988 Fall; VHS videocassette (Cassette 59)
  This is a 30 second advertisement for the America's Opening Pro Cup in Park City, Utah, Thanksgiving, 1988. There are various shots of ski competitions and sights around Park City set to instrumental music.
- TV 45 marketing promotional video, winter season, 1988-1989; VHS videocassette (Cassette 60)
  Poor quality VHS copy of local Park City television station TV 45's yearly marketing promotional video. The tape shows television and community highlights from the previous year in Park City, Utah. Marketing Director: Kim Steit.
- Utah Ski Ball, 1988; U-matic videocassette (Cassette 61)
  A dress rehearsal of a dance troupe preparing for a performance at the 1988 Utah Ski Ball. The camera is in a fixed position throughout the duration of the tape's length while dancers perform on a recently constructed stage. There is also footage of electricians, etc. working on the last-minute preparations for the performance.
- Utah Ski Ball, 1988; U-matic videocassette (Cassette 62)
  This tape contains images from the Utah Ski Ball in 1988. A man, who seems to be the evening's master of ceremonies, speaks about the silent auction. He then introduces the following people: Spence Eccles, Craig Badami, the CEO of the U.S. Ski Association (Howard Peterson), the director of the U.S. Ski Education fund (John Wilson), and a few other names including two female athletes who join the M.C. on stage. The camera remains on the M.C. throughout this presentation. Suzy Harris Rytting addresses the audience. Next, the dance troupe from cassette 37 performs for the audience at the Ski Ball. The M.C., who introduces Merrill Osmond of the Osmond Family, follows them. Mr. Osmond sings a number of songs and interacts with the audience.
- Utah Ski Ball (continued), 1988; U-matic videocassette (Cassette 63)
  This tape contains more images of Merrill Osmond singing. During his performance, Craig Badami gets onstage with him and together they sing, clap and try to get the audience to join in with the clapping. There are shots of the audience dancing and clapping in time.
- Senators Ski Cup, 1989 January 14; VHS videocassette (Cassette 64)
  The Senators Ski Cup is a race that is held annually at the Park City Resort. This event was organized by former Senator Jake Garn to benefit the Primary Children's Hospital and raises around 100,000 dollars through friendly head to head slalom races. After showing footage of various senators racing, the sponsors are interviewed. These sponsors include American Express, Park City Ski Area, Delta Airlines, U.S. West, BMI, First Security, Lucas Aerospace, and Textron.
- News Travel Network: Park City Ski Area, 1989 January 16; VHS videocassette (Reel 65)
  This promotional tape for Park City Ski Area aired on the News Travel Network as a five part series. The episodes highlight Park City's mining history, the various recreational activities in and around Park City, the convenience of traveling to the ski area and lodging and dining in Park City.
- Television news coverage, 1989 January 25-30; VHS videocassette (Cassette 66)
  1/25/89 "Salt Lake City hopes for 1998 Olympics". This news report covers the Olympic Committee selecting their favorite sites for the Olympics and the four venue plans that they are considering. In all of these plans, the cottonwood canyons are excluded due to environmental concerns.
  1/27/89 "Ski Tax Bill". In this edition the pros and cons of the Ski Tax Bill are discussed.
  1/28/89 "U.S. Journalists Visit The Wasatch Front". Nine U. S journalists visit Park City Ski Area, Snowbird, Sundance, and Snow Basin. After their visit, they give their brief thoughts on the Wasatch Front.
  1/29/89 "Disabled Ski Championships". In this report various disabled skiers are interviewed and clips from the race are aired.
  1/30/89 "Ski Resort Operators Convention at Park City Ski Area" This is a report on a convention that was designed to bring business to various manufacturers of mechanical parts for ski resorts.
- Skiing on the rocks, 1989 February 05-09; VHS videocassette (Cassette 67)
  This five part series on the struggles of the Utah ski industry was produced by KUTV news. Reporters claim that Utah resorts are falling behind the industry and cannot afford to catch up due to the Utah sales tax burden. As a consequence, several ski resorts are sold and some claim bankruptcy. In an interview with Snowbird's manager he discusses how the competition is beating Utah resorts and what Utah resorts plan to do to reach the top of the industry.
- Koalafier, 1989 February 28; VHS videocassette (Cassette 68)
  This is a 30 second advertisement for a ski competition. The competition is sponsored by 7-11, KJQFM, Koala springs, and MTV. The two dual slalom skiers who win the race will win a trip to Australia.
- Ski It to Believe It, 1989 September 07; Audiocassette (Cassette 69)
  This tape contains four promotional songs for the skiing industry. Each of them encourages inexperienced skiers to get up to the slopes because you 'have to ski it to believe it'.
  60 Second - Regional / Call Outs
  60 Second - Ski Area / Call Outs
  60 Second - Ski Shop / Call Outs
  30 Second - Instruments With Singer Tag
- Park City Ski Area: pre-season, 1989; Audiocassette, reel-to-reel audiotape (Cassette 70)
  This tape contains three sixty-second advertisements for Park City Ski Area's season passes and other discount tickets: "Ski Party" and "Ski the Best For Less." The advertisements follow the format of the game show Jeopardy.
- America's Opening World Cup advertisement, 1989 October 25; VHS videocassette (Cassette 71)
  This tape contains an advertisement for America's Opening World Cup event held at Park City, Utah over Thanksgiving weekend 1989. The advertisement highlights times, dates, event locations and ticket information and is narrated by a woman.
- America's Opening World Cup advertisement, 1989 October 25; VHS videocassette (Cassette 72)
  This tape contains an advertisement for America's Opening World Cup event held at Park City Utah over Thanksgiving weekend 1989. The advertisement highlights times, dates, event locations and ticket information and is narrated by a man.
- America's Opening World Cup advertisement, 1989 October 26; VHS videocassette, Betacam videocassette (Cassette 73)
  This tape contains an advertisement for America's Opening World Cup event held the Park City Ski Resort over the Thanksgiving weekend in 1989. The advertisement highlights times, dates, event locations and ticket information and is narrated by both a man and a woman.
- America's Opening World Cup advertisement, 1989 October; VHS videocassette (Cassette 74)
  This tape contains an advertisement for America's Opening World Cup event held at the Park City Ski Resort over the Thanksgiving weekend in 1989. The add highlights times, dates, event locations and ticket information and is not narrated.
- CNN Travel Guide - Park City Utah, 1989 November 06-10; VHS videocassette (Cassette 75)
  This video contains the same footage as cassette 65 but was aired on CNN's travel program. The program highlights the history of Park City and how it evolved from an old silver mining town into a booming ski haven, how Park City is developing in order to become the ultimate Olympic venue, how to avoid long lift lines and where to ski and what types of recreation Park City has to offer in addition to the great downhill skiing.
- America's Opening World Cup, 1989 November 22; Betacam videocassette (Cassette 76)
  This videocassette contains the opening ceremonies held at the University of Utah where senator Jake garner offers a warm welcome and congratulations to the athletes competing in the world cup. Following this, the U.S. Alpine Ski Team director speaks. Next they show clips from the actual races and the awards ceremony. Continued on 77.
- America's Opening World Cup, 1989 November 22; Betacam videocassette, VHS videocassette (Cassette 77)
  Continued from 76. This tape contains footage from the Utah Ski Ball, dancing, and entertainment from musicians such as Ed Ames. This is followed by clips from the women's slalom and giant slalom races along with the official results from the two races.
- Park City street dance, 1989 November 22; Betacam videocassette, U-matic videocassette, VHS videocassette (Cassette 78)
  The Park City Street Dance accompanies the coming of the America's Opening event each year. It is a celebration of the love for skiing as well as an event to congratulate the athletes who compete in an America's Opening event. The street dance includes live outdoor music and dancing.
- U.S. Pro Cup camera footage, 1989 November 22; VHS videocassette (Cassette 79)
  This video contains raw footage of the street dance and fireworks, the 1989 U.S. Pro Cup women's and men's giant slalom race, the crowds dancing and cheering and the flag parade.
- U.S. Pro Cup camera footage, 1989 November 22; VHS videocassette (Cassette 80)
  This video contains raw footage of the women's giant slalom race, the men's giant slalom race, and the awards ceremonies.
- Aerials and mineshafts, 1989 November 22; U-matic videocassette (Cassette 81)
  This video contains an aerial view of Park City's mountains, ski runs, and mineshafts during the winter season.
- Park City death, 1989 November 28; VHS videocassette (Cassette 82)
  This tape contains a 30 second news clip covering a helicopter crash in Park City, Utah.
- America's Opening World Cup: women's slalom, 1989 November; VHS videocassette (Cassette 83)
  This video features the first and second runs of the women's World Cup slalom event. In addition to showing each competitor in the course, the film reviews the racers past accomplishments, current standings and future goals and reports on course conditions, weather conditions, and wins by course.
- Utah Ski Ball, 1989; U-matic videocassette (Cassette 84)
  This video contains footage of the auctioning of trips and cars from which all proceeds go to the U.S. Ski Team. After the auction, there is live music from Ted Miller and the High Rollers and Bobby Freeman. The live music and entertainment is continued on cassette 85.
- Utah Ski Ball, 1989; U-matic videocassette (Cassette 85)
  Continued from 84. More footage of live music and entertainment. The artists featured include Leon Use and the Coasters and Joe Muscalini.
- Television news coverage, 1989 November 16; 1989 November 22; 1989 November 30; VHS videocassette (Cassette 86)
  This video contains reports on the importance of the World Cup. The reporters emphasize the fact that the World Cup acts as a tourist attraction, which in turn raises ski revenues. They emphasize the importance of improving Park City Ski Area's snow making technology so that they can always supply a reliable course for the World Cup events regardless of the weather.
- America's Opening World Cup television news coverage, 1989 November 19-25; VHS videocassette (Cassette 87)
  11/19/89 KUTV 10 pm "Lack of snow may cause difficulties"
  11/21/89 KTVX 5:30 pm "Women's ski team trains in karate"
  11/22/89 KUTV 5 pm "World Cup in Park City"
  6 pm "World Cup begins and Park City spends the most to help the Olympic Bid"
  KTVX 10 pm "preparations for the World Cup include making snow"
  11/23/89 KSL 6 pm "World Cup is an important event for Utah's ski future and World Cup is underway"
  10 pm "World Cup Opens and World Cup underway"
  KUTV 5 pm "Snow machines save World Cup"
  6 pm "Ski industry suffers this thanksgiving except Park City, who is hosting World Cup and World Cup Coverage"
  10 pm "World Cup action"
  KTVX 5:30 pm "World Cup"
  6 pm "World Cup could influence the Olympic bid and a look at the World Cup and a look at preparations for the World Cup"
  11/24/89 KSL 6 pm "women's events at the World Cup"
  10 pm "women's events"
  KUTV 5 pm "women's day at the World Cup"
  6 pm "World Cup and the Olympic bid"
  10 pm "World Cup and Olympic Bid and
  World Cup highlights"
  KTVX 5:30 pm "World Cup successful and international attention, World Cup day for Women"
  10 pm "international media and women's races highlighted"
  KUTV 6 pm "Profile of the media coverage"
  KUTV 6 pm "Today's Action"
  KTVX 10 pm "Snow fall helps course"
  KTVX 10 pm "Today's action"
  KSL 5:30 pm "Cancellation"
  KSL 10 pm
  Sports Beat "Wrap up report"
  11/26/89 KUTV 5:30 pm "Cancellation"
  KUTV 10 pm
  KTVX 10 pm
  KTVX 10 pm "Wrap up on results"
- America's Opening World Cup, 1989 November; VHS videocassette (Cassette 88)
  This is an overview of the four-day Thanksgiving weekend World Cup event. The film casts the event as a celebration of accomplishments and a time to share an international love for skiing and features footage of the races, the crowds going wild, and the street dance held in Park City, Utah with live music and dancing.
- "Park City Ski", "America's Opening", 1989 November; Audiocassette (Cassette 89)
  This tape contains two sixty-second advertisements for the America's Opening World Cup event held at the Park City Ski Resort over the Thanksgiving weekend in 1989. The add highlights times, dates, the event schedule and special events such as live music and dancing as well as ticket information. Danny Jessop on the radio station Magic 107.5 aired these advertisements.
- Craig Badami memorial parts 1-2, 1989 December 2; Reel-to-reel audiotape (Reel 90)
  This audiotape contains the memorial services for Craig Badami who was the Vice President of Park City Ski Area. C.B., as he liked to be called, handled the promoting and marketing for Park City Ski Area in addition to bringing the America's Opening World Cup Event to Park City. The services where broadcasted live over the radio station KPCW. While waiting for services to begin, the radio announcer reads through the program, announces the pasture as well as the speakers and the musical interlude. The services then begin with an opening invocation and prayer. Then the pasture reads several letters from various members of the Men's and Women's U.S. Ski Team, all honoring Craig's hard work. Following this, five of C.B's close friends share their own memories of his hard work and fun personality. The musical interlude was offered by C.B's very own band, Johnny and the P.C Rockers. The band then presents Nicholas Badami, Craig's son, with his harmonica. Five more friends share their loving memories and the service is brought to a close with a benediction.
- TV 45 avalanche story, Warren Miller feature, Al's Hill feature, 1989; VHS videocassette (Cassette 91)
  This video contains three news reports:
  The first is a story on avalanches. It includes avalanche statistics, the definition of the three different types of avalanches along with footage of each type, and information on what to do if you are ever caught in an avalanche.
  The second report is a story on the upcoming Warren Miller production, Extreme Winter.
  The third is a news report on a ski event named Al's Challenge. This ski event is a relay race that takes place during spring skiing. This coverage ends abruptly.
- On The Move, 1989; VHS videocassette (Cassette 92)
  This is a promotional video for the U.S. Ski Team. It contains comments from the coaches and racers concerning the development of the team as well as comments from the sponsors on why they have chosen to support the team. There is also a brief explanation of each U.S. Ski Team event, what is required of the athletes as far as training, and why it is so important that the World Championships has finally opened in America.
- "Higher Ground" three minute version, 1989; Audiocasette (Cassette 93)
  This is a three-minute promotional song for the Utah Winter Games. Written by Judd Maher and Sam Cardon.
- Jimmie Heuga Center, 1989; VHS videocassette (Cassette 94)
  This video is a John Sandy production and portrays the life story of Jimmie Heuga. The Jimmie Heuga Center was created to give physically challenged people a second chance by focusing on what they can do rather than on what they cannot.
- Salomon Bindings, circa 1989-1990; VHS videocassette (Cassette 95)
  Promotional video about Salomon bindings. The film explains the mechanics behind the bindings and the materials used in developing safer and lighter bindings and shows the various bindings produced by Salomon for different levels and types of skiers.
- Holly Flanders news special, 1990 January 06; VHS videocassette (Cassette 96)
  In this news special they discuss Flanders' past skiing accomplishments, current endeavors and future goals. Flanders also discusses her transition from world wide competitive skier to public relations employee at Park City Ski Area.
- Rossignol advertisement, 1990 January 10; VHS videocassette (Cassette 97)
  This tape contains a thirty-second advertisement for Rossignol skis and boots.
- Subaru's fanfare to U.S. Skiing, 1990 October 02; VHS videocassette (Cassette 98)
  Promotional video for the U.S. Ski Team and Subaru's sponsorship of them. It reviews the history of Subaru's sponsorship of the team and the history and future of U.S. Ski racing. 12:31.
- Park City Pro Cup advertisement, 1990 November 05; VHS videocassette (Cassette 99)
  This video contains thirty-seconds of an advertisement for the Pro Cup event held at Park City Ski Area. It shows the beautiful mountains of Park City and a Pro Cup racer skiing the gates. The video ends abruptly.
- U.S. Pro Cup races advertisement, 1990 November 07; Betacam videocassette, VHS videocassette (Cassette 100)
  This is a thirty-second advertisement for the fifth annual Pro Cup Ski Tour held at Park City Ski Area. The add includes information on times, dates and ticket information.
- America's Opening World Cup: women's slalom, 1990 November 24; VHS videocassette (Cassette 101)
  This video contains ESPN's coverage of the 1990 World Cup women's slalom event. It begins with highlights from the first run and the corresponding results. Then VISA sponsors a profile of Eva Twardokens that includes a short interview. Next Nordica sponsors a ski fact, in this case, the difference between slalom and giant slalom skis. The second run of the women's slalom event is broadcasted live followed by a report of the final standings.
- U.S. Pro Cup raw race footage from Extreme Novo, 1990 November 24-25; VHS videocassette (Cassette 102)
  This video contains footage of the street dance and fireworks held in the streets of Park City Utah along with the flag parade, balloon release, and the men's 1990 U.S. Pro Cup awards ceremony.
  The next footage is of the 1990 U.S. Pro Cup Women's giant slalom race followed by the awards ceremony.
- Soldier honored at Park City, 1990 November 25; VHS videocassette (Cassette 103)
  This video contains a report on a marine named William Thompson who saved six other marines during the Vietnam War. He is honored at Park City Ski Area with a bronze star metal.
  This story is followed by a memorial for Craig Badami (1952-1989). In the memorial Mark Menlove offers memories of his friend and co-worker, they honor his accomplishments, and show past clips of various interviews with Craig himself.
- U.S. Pro Cup raw race footage, 1990 November 25; VHS videocassette (Cassette 104)
  This video contains raw footage of the 1990 U.S. Pro Cup race held at Park City Ski Area. The footage includes a view of the race course and the crowds, a ceremony in which Captain William Thompson is honored with a bronze star metal (see 103 for more details), the women's giant slalom race, and the awards ceremony.
- U.S. Pro Cup Ski Tour, America's Opening slalom event, 1990 November 25; VHS videocassette (Cassette 105)
  This video features the U.S. Pro Cup race at Park City Ski Area. The announcers give a brief history of America's Opening Pro Cup then they review the course conditions, the fastest qualifiers, the American qualifiers, and explain how a Pro Cup race is put on.
  The video features runs from the rounds of 32 and 16, the quarterfinals, semifinals and the finals. Race results are reported throughout.
- U.S. Pro Cup Ski Tour, America's Opening giant slalom event, 1990 November; VHS videocassette (Cassette 106)
  This video features the U.S. Pro Cup race at Park City Ski Area. The announcers list the locations that the Pro Cup races visit on tour, they give a brief ski history on the top two racers and give a course description.
  The video features runs from the rounds of 32 and 16, the quarterfinals, semifinals and the finals. Throughout the race the announcers report the race results and host brief interviews with various racers.
- America's Opening Pro Cup days 1-2, 1990 November; Hi-8 videocassette (Cassette 107)
  Starts, bumps, finish, flag parade and balloons, awards, races and announcers.
- Extreme Winter, 1990; VHS videocassette (Cassette 108)